					<div class="item item-talk">
						<div class="meta">
							<h4 class="time mb-3">08:00 - 08:30</h4>
							<div class="profile">
								<a href="#modal-speaker-1" data-bs-toggle="modal" data-bs-target="#modal-speaker-1"><img class="profile-image rounded-circle  mb-2" src="assets/images/speakers/55_Quispe.png" alt=""></a>
								<div class="name"><a class="theme-link" href="#modal-speaker-1" data-bs-toggle="modal" data-bs-target="#modal-speaker-1">Fredi Quispe Huaynasi</a></div>
							</div><!--//profile-->
						</div><!--//meta-->
						<div class="content">
							<h3 class="title mb-3">Estrellas con alta velocidad en la Vía Láctea</h3>
							<div class="desc"> <p align="justify"> Estrellas con alta velocidad en la Vía Láctea están asociados a fenómenos astrofísicos extremos como: 
                            Explosión de supernovas en sistemas binarios de estrellas, interacción de estrellas binarias con agujeros negros, resultado de fusión de galaxias con nuestra Galaxia, entre otros. 
							En está charla será expuesta una introducción sobre el origen y descubrimiento de las estrellas 
                            con alta velocidad, búsqueda y caracterización de estrellas con alta velocidad usando recientes catálogos estelares. </p> </div>
						</div><!--//content-->
					</div><!--//item-->

					<div class="item item-talk">
						<div class="meta">
							<h4 class="time mb-3">08:35 - 09:05</h4>
							<div class="profile">
								<a href="#modal-speaker-1" data-bs-toggle="modal" data-bs-target="#modal-speaker-1"><img class="profile-image rounded-circle  mb-2" src="assets/images/speakers/55_Lebron.png" alt=""></a>
								<div class="name"><a class="theme-link" href="#modal-speaker-1" data-bs-toggle="modal" data-bs-target="#modal-speaker-1">Mayra E. Lebrón Santos</a></div>
							</div><!--//profile-->
						</div><!--//meta-->
						<div class="content">
							<h3 class="title mb-3">Arecibo confirms infrared ZoA galaxies selected from spitzer data</h3>
							<div class="desc"><p align="justify">We report the detection of 7 new galaxies in HI in the deepest 
                            regions of the Zone of Avoidance using the Arecibo Telescope. The detected galaxies are part of a sample of 25 sources, 
                            identified as galaxies using IR images from the SPITZER Space Telescope by Marleau et al 2008. The sample is composed of 
                            disk galaxies as it was one of the source identification criteria in their survey. None of the sources have optical counterparts. 
                            The velocity of the new galaxies in HI are between 5,700 km s-1 and 10,900 km s-1 and their estimated masses range from 1.5 x 10⁹ to 1.3 x 1010 solar masses. 
                            Although the studied region is part of two HI blind searches, none of our sources were detected in HI previously. 
                            Blind searches are optimized to cover large areas of sky but are not very deep. 
                            Due to the HI intensities of the detected galaxies, none of them could be detected in this type of search. 
                            HI observations of specific candidates allows more in-depth observations than blind searches but requires candidate lists to be established. 
                            That is not possible in optical for the ZoA. 
                            The results of this work shows that the identification of galaxies in the ZoA using IR data such as that of Marleau et al. 2008 
                            is a viable way to study the deepest areas of the ZoA, providing candidates for further HI observations. Motivated by these results, 
                            we have continued to work with the SPITZER Space Telescope archived data to identify new candidates in the ZoA. This work is in preparation.</p></div>
						</div><!--//content-->
					</div><!--//item-->
